Maryanne Exempliarova

UX/UI Designer

1	Argentina, Buenos Aires
\bigvee	exemaryanne@gmail.com
	maryanne-exe.github.io
in	linkedin.com/in/marvannexe

Summary

User experience designer who believes that this work is about seeing a big picture, being empathetic and building right design process. Communicative team player and enthusiastic problem solver with endless curiosity to all aspects of the project. Expert in a variety of UX guidelines, platforms, and UI patterns; familiar with UI development.

Work History

UX/UI Designer

Mar 2016 - Present

Eturnity

Chur, Switzerland, Remote contractor

User experience designer in Switzerland renewable energy startup. Now my responsibilities are:

- Detecting improvements areas and analyze usability problems in the web-based application UI;
 - Collaboration with developers on the design of new features;
 - Development and maintenance of web-based style guideline;
- Design of low-fidelity and pixel-perfect mockups, delivering design solutions to the development team.

UX/UI Designer

Sep 2015 - Mar 2016

Freelance

Buenos Aires, Argentina

User experience for mobile and web applications. Areas of expertise:

- User experience development of mobile applications in strong compliance with Apple HIG and Material Design guidelines;
 - Development of well-branded and effective user experience for web-based services;
- Application evaluation according to the usability heuristics and the best practices based on project priorities;
 - Translating abstract concepts into simple and elegant user interfaces;
 - Providing with effective iterative design process.

Lead UX/UI Designer

Jan 2015 - Aug 2015

JSC Radiomonitoring Technologies

St. Petersburg, Russia

Work on several top secret software products for security radio monitoring for desktop (Windows, Linux) and mobile platforms (Windows phone and Android). My role:

Detect and analyze usability problems of legacy UIs;

- Embed UX stage in products' development workflow;
- Develop low-fidelity mockups and pixel-perfect designs;
- Work with guidelines: Material, Windows Modern Design, also create custom consistent and clear UIs;
- Develop and maintain style guides;
- Deliver designs for UI developers and checking the progress of development for the design compliance.

UX/UI Designer

Aug 2014 - Nov 2014

<u>JetBrains</u> St. Petersburg, Russia

Work on TeamCity continuous integration server. My responsibilities:

- Identify and analyze issues in current web interface;
- Uniform UI regarding guidelines of other company's products;
- Create low-fidelity and pixel-perfect mockups;
- Prepare designs for UI developers and monitor process of its realization.

UX/UI Designer

Jan 2014 - Aug 2014

NKS

St. Petersburg, Russia

Taking part in developing web-based news service and iOS application for delivering food using Xamarin Studio. My role was to improve the usability of news service and design iOS application from scratch.

3D Artist

Aug 2013 - Jan 2014

wargaming.net

St. Petersburg, Russia

My role was to develop realistic historical based 3d models of World War II naval ships and draw freehand pixel-perfect textures for World of Warships video game.

Junior .NET Developer

Sep 2011 - Aug 2013

Lifeactive

St. Petersburg, Russia

Take part in UI development of web-based applications.

Education

Bachelor's degree

2009 - 2013

Saint Petersburg State Polytechnic University

Applied Computer Science in Design

Coursera certificate

2016

University of California, San Diego

Interaction Design Specialization